Reinhold Niebuhr Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speech, Article, and Book File, 1913-1965 (Box 14-23)
  - Articles (Box 15)
    - "Prospects of the Christian Gospel in Future America"
    - "The Real Question about Religion"
    - "The Relation of European to American Culture"
    - "Religion and Poetry"
    - "Religion and the Freedom of the Mind"
    - "Religion's Limitations"
    - "Religiosity Versus the Christian Gospel"
    - "The Religious Assumptions of Adam Smith"
    - "The Religious Assumptions of Karl Marx"
    - "The Religious Traditions of Our Nation and the Problems of a Technical Civilization in a Nuclear Age"
    - "The Renewal of Religious Faith in America"
    - "The Republican Record" (Box 17)
    - "The Revival of Religion in America"
    - "The Rise in American Prestige"
    - "The Rising Tide of Color"
    - "Russia and America"
    - "The Secularism and Piety of America"
    - "The Self"
    - "Sin"
    - "The Suez Crisis and the Post-Stalin Era"
    - "The Specialist"
    - "The Task of American Liberalism"
    - "The Tasks of Liberalism in America"
    - "The Teamsters and the Future of Unionism"
    - "Theology and Political Thought in the Western World"
    - "A Third of a Century at Union Seminary"
    - "Tolerance"
    - "The Ultimate Validity and the Ideological Distortions of Moral Concepts in International Politics"
    - "The Union of the Congregational and Evangelical and Reformed Churches"
    - "The United Nations and the World Community"
    - "The United Nations Is Not a World Government"
    - "The Unpredictable Emergencies of History"
    - "The Value of a Constitutionally Pegged Ideal"
    - "The War and Religion"
    - "The West and Asia"
    - "What to Do About Insults to Others"
    - "The World I Would Like to Live In"
    - Untitled articles
  - Reviews
    - Daniel Bell, Work and Its Discontents
    - Isaiah Berlin, The Hedgehog and the Fox
    - Isaiah Berlin, Historical Inevitability
    - Jim Bishop, The Day Christ Died
    - Daniel J. Boorstin, The Genius of American Politics
    - Guiseppe Antonio Borgese, Foundations of the World Republic
    - Martin Buber, Pointing the Way
    - James MacGregor Burns, Roosevelt: The Lion and the Fox
    - Herbert Butterfield, Christianity, Diplomacy and War
    - Algernon Cecil, A House in Bryanston Square
    - James Collins, The Mind of Kierkegaard
    - J. Harry Cotton, Royce and the Human Self
    - Norman Cousins, Who Speaks for Man?
    - M. C. D'Arcy, The Meaning and Matter of History
    - Charles Galton Darwin, The Next Million Years
    - A. Powell Davies, The Urge to Persecute
    - Elmer Davis, Two Minutes to Midnight
    - Charles A. Fecher, The Philosophy of Jacques Maritain
    - Etienne Gilson, History of Christian Philosophy in the Middle Ages
    - Nahum N. Glatzer, Franz Rosenzweig
    - J. Edgar Goodspeed, As I Remember
    - Robert Graves and Joshua Podro, The Nazarene Gospel Restored
    - Marjorie Grene, Heidegger; Arthur Cohen
      - Martin Buber; and Ian W. Alexander, Bergson
    - Carleton J. H. Hayes, Christianity and Western Civilization (Box 18)
    - Karl Heim, The Transformation of the Scientific World View
    - Will Herberg, Protestant-Catholic-Jew
    - Abraham Joshua Heschel, God in Search of Man
    - Gilbert Highet, Man's Unconquerable Mind
    - William Ernest Hocking, The Strength of Men and Nations
    - Johannes Hohlenberg, Soren Kierkegaard
    - Sidney Hook, Heresy, Yes - Conspiracy, No
    - Sidney Hook (ed.), Philosophers at Work
    - Trevor Huddleston, Naught for Your Comfort
    - Karl Jaspers, The Future of Mankind
    - Douglas Jerrold, The Lie about the West
    - B. B. Keet, Whither South Africa
    - Murray Kempton, Part of Our Time
    - Arthur Koestler, The Invisible Writing
    - Arthur Koestler, Reflections on Hanging
    - Joseph Wood Krutch, The Measure of Man
    - Umphrey Lee, God's Horseman
    - Leo Lerner, The Itch of Opinion
    - Walter Lippmann, The Public Philosophy
    - Perry Miller, The New England Mind
    - Albert Outler, Psycho-Therapy and the Christian
    - G. Bromley Oxnam, My Experience With the House Committee on Un-American Activities
    - Lord Percy, The Heresy of Democracy
    - Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan, Recovery of Faith
    - Charles E. Raven, Natural Religion and Christian Theology
    - P. B. Rice, On the Knowledge of Good and Evil
    - Russell of Liverpool, Edward Frederick Langley Russell, Baron, The Scourge of the Swastika
    - Bertrand Russell, Why I Am Not a Christian, and Other Essays on Religion and Related Subjects
      - Maurice Samuel, The Professor and the Fossil
    - Arnold Toynbee, An Historian's Approach to Religion
    - Peter Viereck, Dream and Responsibility
  - Printed articles and reviews
    - Christianity and Crisis, Vols. II-IV, 1942-1944
    - Miscellaneous articles and reviews, (15 folders); (9 folders) (Box 19, Box 20)
    - Report, The Negro in Detroit
  - Books (Box 21)
    - Foreword to Robert Angell's Democracy and Moral Integration
    - Foreword to Leon Poliakov's Harvest of Shame
    - Introduction to Wilbur Schramm's Responsibility in Mass Communications
    - Pious and Secular America
    - The Self and the Dramas of History
    - Man's Nature and His Communities, (12 folders); (4 folders) (Box 22)
    - The Democratic Experience (with Paul Sigmund)
    - The Structure of Nations and Empires (Box 23)
- Miscellany (Box 24-25)
  Biographical material, class lectures, printed matter, photographs, and other miscellaneous items or files.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - B.D. thesis, "The Validity and Certainty of Religious Knowledge," 1914 (Box 24)
  - Bibliographies
  - Biographical material
  - CARE Inc. receipts
  - Class lectures
    - Christian ethics
    - Communism seminar
    - Doctrine of man (Box 25)
    - Interpretation of history
  - Engagement calendars, 1932-1939
  - Photographs
  - Printed matter
- June Bingham Correspondence (Box 26-27)
  Arranged alphabetically except for Bingham's correspondence with Niebuhr that precedes other correspondence.
  - Reinhold Niebuhr, 1952-1963, undated, (9 folders) (Box 26)
  - Acheson, Dean
  - "A" miscellaneous
  - Bennett, John C.
  - "B - C" miscellaneous
  - Dun, Angus
  - "D" miscellaneous
  - Elliston, Herbert Berridge
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Fromm, Erich
  - "F" miscellaneous
  - Gill, Brendan
  - "G" miscellaneous
  - Herberg, Will
  - Hook, Sidney
  - "H - I" miscellaneous
  - Kirchway, Freda
  - Koestler, Arthur
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood
  - "K" miscellaneous
  - Lippmann, Walter
  - Lister, R. P.
  - "L" miscellaneous
  - Maritain, Jacques
  - "M" miscellaneous
  - Niebuhr, Hulda
  - Niebuhr, Lydia
  - Niebuhr, Ursula
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert (Box 27)
  - Press, Samuel D.
  - "P" miscellaneous
  - Reston, James
  - Reuther, Walter P.
  - Russell, Bertrand
  - "R" miscellaneous
  - Scarlett, William
  - Schiff, Dorothy
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1917-2007)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1965)
  - "S" miscellaneous
  - Thomas, Norman
  - Tillich, Paul
  - "U - V" miscellaneous
  - West, Anthony
  - "W - Z" miscellaneous
  - Unidentified
- Reinhold Niebuhr Correspondence Collected by June Bingham (Box 27)
  Niebuhr correspondence with persons other than Bingham.
  - Niebuhr to (Box 27)
    - Elliston, Herbert Berridge
    - Frankfurter, Felix
    - Mann, Thomas
    - Press, Samuel D.
    - Riesman, David
    - Scarlett, William
    - Schiff, Dorothy
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1917-2007)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation
    - Wyzanski, Charles E.
  - Niebuhr family correspondence
- June Bingham Book File (Box 28-32)
  Papers relating to Bingham's biography of Niebuhr, Courage to Change.
  Organized by type of material.
  - Courage to Change (Box 28-31)
  - Courage to Change (Box 32)
  - Miscellany
- William Scarlett Correspondence, 1958-1971 (Box 33)
  Letters from Niebuhr to Scarlett and related and attached material.
  Organized chronologically.
  - 1958-1971, undated, (7 folders) (Box 33)
- Addition I, 1914-1976 (Box 34-41)
  - Subject File, 1928-1976 (Box 34-37)
    Correspondence, printed matter, and related background material.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic or name of person or organization.
    - Americans for Democratic Action, 1967-1971 (Box 34)
    - Auden, W. H., 1941-1972
      - Correspondence
      - Poems and Copies
      - Typescript
    - Christianity and Crisis, 1972-1973
    - Condolence, letters of, A-Z, 1971, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Criticism of White House sermons
    - Hebrew University of Jerusalem degree, 1967-1972, undated
    - Heinemann, Gustav, 1972-1975
    - Iowa College, Grinnell, Iowa, doctor of divinity degree, 1932
    - Loeb, James I., 1974
    - Miller, William R., 1969
    - Miscellany, A-Z, 1959-1972
    - Morris, Ivor, 1970
    - Mosley, J. Brooke, 1971-1973
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1969-1972, (2 folders)
    - Obituary notices, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Printed matter, 1928, 1971-1972, undated
    - Reinhold Niebuhr Award, 1971-1975, (6 folders)
    - Reinhold Niebuhr Professorship Fund, Union Theological Seminary, New York, N.Y., 1958-1976, undated (Box 37)
    - Rose, Stephen C., 1970-1971
    - "Serenity Prayer," 1966-1972, 1975
    - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1965), 1954-1957, 1973
    - Turnbull, John W., 1971
    - Union Theological Seminary, Richmond, Va., sound recordings of sermons, 1962-1974, undated
  - Writings, 1967-1975 (Box 38-41)
    Articles, books, sermons, reviews, speeches and related materials.
    - Articles, A-W, (25 folders) (Box 38)
    - Books (Box 39)
      - Faith and Politics
        - Corrected manuscript, (5 folders)
        - Correspondence and reviews, 1967-1969
      - Justice and Mercy
        - Drafts, (2 folders) (Box 40)
        - Correspondence and reviews, 1974-1975, undated, (3 folders)
      - Man's Nature and His Communities, unpublished introduction
      - Nature and Destiny of Man, corrected galleys
    - Class lectures (Box 41)
    - Reviews
    - Sermons, (6 folders)
    - Speeches
  - Oversize, 1914-1955 (Box OV 1)
    Certificates and photograph.
    Arranged and described according to the series and containers from which the items were removed.
    - Certificates, 1914, 1947-1955 (Box OV 1)
    - Photograph of Yale University Divinity School class of 1914, New Haven, Conn.
- Addition II, 1930-1972 (Box 42-45)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1972 (Box 42)
    Letters received and a few copies of letters sent.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization.
    - Ball, Robert M., 1965 (Box 42)
    - Bennett, John C., 1930-1972
    - Conant, James Bryant, 1969-1970
    - Library of Congress, 1970-1971
    - New Republic, 1966
    - Schneider, Mrs. (?), 1971
    - Yale University Library, New Haven, Conn., 1970-1971
  - Writings, 1951-1961 (Box 42-45)
    Articles, book chapters, reviews, addresses, sermons, prayers, and lecture notes.
    Arranged by type of material and thereunder alphabetically by title.
    - Book chapters (books mainly unidentified) (Box 42)
      - "Co-Existence between Communistic and Democratic Powers"
      - "Democracy, Communism and Justice in an Industrial Society"
      - Democracy in Non-European Cultures
      - "Industrialization and the Social Struggle"
      - "The Problem of Diversity in Language, Race, and Culture"
      - "Divisions of Race, Language and Religion in Old and New Nations"
      - "Dogma and Common Experience: The Relation of Strength to Weakness in the World Community"
      - "The Free World -- Is Democracy a Simple Alternative to Communism or an Ultimate Political Ideal?"
      - "The Hazards of Democracy in Non-European Cultures" (fragments)
      - "International Politics Under the Sword of Damocles"
      - "Novel and Perennial Factors in Modern Global Politics"
      - "The Peril of Technical Progress to Human Culture" (Box 43)
      - "The Power Relations in Communistic and Democratic Regimes"
        - "Reflections on a Semi-Christian and Semi-Secular Age," introduction to Man's Nature and His Communities, 1965
      - "The Roots in Western Culture of Both Democracy and Communism"
      - "Technics, Poverty, Justice and Civilization"
      - "The Two Imperial Nations in an Anti-Imperialistic Age"
      - "The Unintended Virtues of an Open Society"
      - "Western Culture and the Global Community"
      - "The World Divided"
      - Untitled fragments
    - Articles
      - "American Hegemony and the Prospects for Peace"
      - "The American Presidency and the Moratorium"
      - "Billy Graham in Historical Perspective"
      - "Catastrophe and Complacency"
      - "The Catholic Church in America"
      - "The Communist Indictment of Bourgeois Democracy..." from New Leader (?), circa 1966
      - "The Conscious and Sub-Conscious Sources of Political Loyalty"
      - "The Difference in Three Decades of American History"
      - "Ferocity in Alabama and Mississippi"
      - "Ford and the Auto Industry of Detroit in 1920s"
      - "Formosa Policy," from Christian Action, 3 March 1955
      - "The Future Problems of the American Economy"
      - "The Ideological Contest"
      - "John C. Bennett, Theologian, Churchman and Educator" from Theology and the Church in Times of Change, 1970 (Box 44)
      - "Liberal Protestantism in America as an Industrial Nation and World Power"
      - "Memorandum on Bicentennial"
      - "Memorandum on the Study of the Humanities in American Colleges and Universities"
      - "Modernizing Nationalism: The Ideologies of the Developing Areas"
      - "The Moral Issue in International Relations"
      - "The Morass of Religiosity in a Pluralistic Society"
      - "The Narrow Gate"
      - "Only a Quarter Century of American Imperial Destiny"
      - "Our Two Youthful Rebellions: The Light They Throw on Our American Culture"
      - "The Real Character of the Contest with Communism"
      - "Selfishness and Unselfishness and Christian Doctrine"
      - "The Student Strike Against War and Our National Self-Discovery"
      - "Why the Christian Church Is Not Pacifist"
    - Review, "The Essays of A. J. Muste"
    - Addresses
      - "Authority and Freedom in the Catholic Church"
      - "Detroit," 21 Apr. 1965, regarding diamond anniversary of Niebuhr's congregation, Bethel Evangelical Church, Detroit, Mich.
      - "The Politics of the 1930s"
      - "Portrait of an Idealist"
      - Untitled, Barnard College, New York, N.Y., 15 May 1961
    - Prayers, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 45)
    - Sermons
      - "Christianity and Crisis"
      - "Has History a Meaning?" (incomplete)
      - "Historical Insecurities and the Final Security"
      - "The Human Condition"
      - "The Impossible Demand for Inner Integrity"
      - "Joy, Sorrow, and Happiness According to the Christian Faith," Union Church, Berea, Ky., 9 Dec. 1951
      - "The Larger Communities of Man"
      - "The Meaning of Existence and the Existence of God" (incomplete)
      - "The Problem of Man's Finiteness, Freedom and Self-Concern"
      - "Problems Confronting Religious Communities Today"
      - Short and incomplete drafts and notes
      - Untitled, in German
      - Untitled, Union Theological Seminary, 13 Nov. 1955
      - Untitled outline
    - Lecture notes
      - Christian ethics
      - Christian ethics 221
      - Christian ethics 222
      - Seminar, 1960-1961
      - Various outlines for courses
  - Miscellany (Box 45)
    Biographical material, clippings, notes, photographs, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material or topic.
    - Biographical file (Box 45)
    - Clippings
    - Notes
    - Photograph
    - Printed matter
- Addition III, 1907-1992 (Box 46-57)
  - Correspondence, 1913-1990 (Box 46-54)
    - Aitken, Barbara See Container 48, Gwyer, B. E. (Box 46)
    - Alinsky, Saul, 1972
    - Angevin, John, 1971-1974
    - Ansons, Susan J., 1965
    - Arndt, Elmer J. F., 1933
    - Baillie, John and Jewel, 1934-1962, undated
    - Baker, Gilbert See Container 47, Clasper, Paul D.
    - Baldwin, Roger N., 1939
    - Barnes, John, 1972-1989, undated
    - Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1954, 1970
    - Bell, William F., 1965-1966, 1988
    - Bennett, John C., 1957-1989, undated For additional material see Container 47, Christianity and Crisis; and Container 55, Fox, Richard, (2 folders)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 1943, 1949-1953, 1969-1982
    - Bingham, Jonathan and June, 1953-1987, undated
    - Bliven, Bruce and Rosie, 1954, 1961-1977, 1985
    - Bowles, Chester B., 1956
    - Bowra, Maurice, 1949, 1958, 1968-1970, undated
    - Brown, Charles, 1989
    - Brown, Robert McAfee, 1967-1989, undated
    - "B" miscellaneous, 1953-1976
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1976-1979
    - Cartwright, Michael G., 1988 (Box 47)
    - Cary, William L. and Katherine, 1961-1971, 1983
    - Case, William W., 1927
    - Centre for Biblical and Jewish Studies, Our Lady of Sion, London, England, 1971, 1980
    - Christian Century, 1938
    - Christianity and Crisis, 1972, 1986-1988, undated
    - Chrystal, William G., 1976-1986
    - Clasper, Paul D., 1969, 1979-1989, undated
    - Clecak, Peter, 1977
    - Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1933, 1946, undated
    - Cogley, John, 1961, 1971-1974
    - Coles, Robert, 1967-1985
    - Conant, James Bryant, 1948-1950
    - Conte, Silvio O., 1967, 1982
    - Cooper, John W., 1982-1986
    - Cripps, Sir Richard Stafford and Isobel, 1939-1958
    - Crocker, John, 1955-1978
    - Cross, Gertie and Leslie, 1930, 1940-1942, 1951, 1970-1973
    - Crothers, George D., 1971-1979
    - "C" miscellaneous, 1926-1989, undated
    - Davies, William David and Eurwen, 1965-1975
    - Davis, Harry Rex, 1953-1960, 1987-1989
    - Decke, Gerd, 1969
    - DeGruchy, John, 1981-1988
    - Denger, Florence, 1970-1975, undated
    - Dodd, C. H. and Phyllis, 1942-1971, undated
    - Dun, Angus and Catherine ("Kitty"), 1956, 1965-1969, undated
    - Dyson, Freeman, 1958, 1979-1980 (Box 48)
    - "D" miscellaneous, 1930, 1942, 1948-1989, undated
    - Egan, John J., 1971-1982, undated
    - Eliot, T. S., 1946-1959
    - Elliott, Elbert, 1970
    - Elmhurst College, Elmhurst, Ill., 1986
    - Erikson, Eric and Joan, 1960-1971, undated
    - Fackre, Gabriel J., 1968-1986
    - Finkelstein, Louis, 1969
    - Flesserman, Ellen, 1947, 1977, 1983
    - Floyd, Richard, 1988-1989
    - Ford, George B., 1975
    - Fosdick, Harry Emerson and Dorothy, 1956, 1969, undated
    - Fox, Richard See Container 55, same heading
    - Frank, Anna, 1969
    - Frankfurter, Felix and Marion, 1942-1964, undated
    - Franklin, Sam H., Jr., 1966-1971, 1982-1990
    - Freund, Paul A., 1956
    - "F" miscellaneous, 1984
    - Gelber, Lionel, 1972
    - Gilkey, Charles Whitney, 1932
    - Gilkey, Langdon, 1988-1989
    - Glueck, Nelson, 1969-1970
    - Good, Robert C. See Container 47, Davis, Harry Rex
    - Gordon, J. King and Ruth Anderson, 1931-1936, 1960-1989, undated
    - Gottsfield, Robert L., 1975
    - Greenlaw, William, 1972-1975, undated
    - Gregg, Richard B., 1935
    - Gwyer, B. E., 1940-1971, undated
    - "G" miscellaneous, 1955, 1966-1974
    - Hadassah, Boston chapter, Boston, Mass., 1975
    - Hall, Douglas, 1966, 1979-1989, undated (Box 49)
    - Hall, Ronald O., 1941-1945, 1957, 1971
    - Harlow, Gretta, 1980-1983, undated
    - Hase, Hans Christoph von, 1934, 1968, 1987-1988, undated
    - Heimert, Alan, 1965-1966, undated
    - Herberg, Will, 1950, 1956-1957, 1965
    - Hodson, H. V., 1965
    - Holmes, John Haynes, 1934
    - Hook, Sidney, 1987
    - Horton, Myles, 1986-1989
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1965-1976
    - Humphries, Bertram and Myra, 1966-1971
    - Hussey, Margaret and Bill, 1980-1989
    - "H" miscellaneous, 1933, 1955, 1964-1981, undated
    - Jesuits, 1971-1989, undated
    - Johnson, J. Dell, 1978
    - Johnson, Kermit, 1982-1988
    - "J" miscellaneous, 1948, 1968-1972
    - Keedy, Allen See Container 48, Fackre, Gabriel J.
    - Kegley, Charles W., 1982-1985
    - Kennan, George F., 1966
    - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1957-1971
    - "K" miscellaneous, 1966-1989
    - LaFarge, Sheila, 1955, 1963
    - Landon, Harold R., 1987-1988
    - Leatt, James V. See Container 47, DeGruchy, John
    - Leibholz, Sabine See Container 55, Bonhoeffer, Dietrich
    - Lincoln College, Lincoln, Ill., 1979
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1929
    - Littell, Franklin H.
      - 1970-1977, (2 folders)
      - 1978-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Loeb, James I., Ellen, and Peter, 1 952, 1961-1979
    - "L" miscellaneous, 1939-1977, undated
    - Merkley, Paul, 1974-1980, 1989
    - Moore, Marianne, 1960
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1965-1970
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1944, 1965-1972
    - "M" miscellaneous, 1959, 1967-1977
    - Nelson, Burton F., 1981-1987
    - Neubauer, Reinhard, 1962, 1984-1986
    - New Leader, 1969-1972
    - Niebuhr, Elisabeth, circa 1960
    - Niemöller, Else, 1952
    - Nunley, Richard, 1985
    - Novak, Michael, 1965-1966
    - "O" miscellaneous, 1956, 1967, undated
    - Paton, Alan, 1975-1988, undated
    - Paton, David M., 1942, 1976-1978
    - Pauck, Wilhelm and Marion
      - 1963-1979, (3 folders)
      - 1980-1988, (1 folder) (Box 51)
    - Peerman, Dean G., 1986-1987
    - Perham, Margery, 1944-1947, 1958
    - Pokorny, Otto A. and Grace, 1966-1976
    - Porter, John F., 1972-1982
    - Proctor, Evelyn, 1948-1958
    - Press, Samuel D., 1913
    - "P" miscellaneous, 1927, 1946-1989
    - Ramsey, Michael, 1962-1972
    - Rasmussen, Larry, 1986-1990, undated
    - Ratcliffe, S. K. and Peggy, 1943-1944, 1952-1953, undated
    - Rice, Daniel F., 1978-1990, undated
    - Robertson, D. B., 1952-1985
    - Rockwell, Norman and Mollie, 1965-1966, undated
    - Rubboli, Massimo, 1985-1986
    - "R" miscellaneous, 1943, 1968-1977
    - Sabin, Albert B. and Amie, 1970, 1986
    - Scarlett, William, 1936, 1964-1974, undated
    - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (1917-2007), 1957-1988, undated For additional material see Container 46, Bingham, Jonathan and June
    - Schlesinger, Elizabeth, 1965
    - Scott, Nathan A., Jr.
      - 1965-1977
      - 1978-1990, undated (Box 52)
    - Shinn, Roger Lincoln, 1969-1970
    - Sigmund, Paul, 1969-1970, undated
    - Simons, Hans, 1965, 1972
    - Smith, John E., 1953-1956, 1968, undated
    - Spender, Stephen, 1955, 1974
    - Splinter, Dieter, 1985-1986
    - Standing Liturgical Commission of the Episcopal Church, 1979, undated
    - Stansgate, Margaret, 1952, 1985-1988, undated
    - Stewart, John B., 1989
    - Stone, Ronald H., 1965-1987
    - "S" miscellaneous, 1933-1935, 1959-1988, undated
    - Theis, Edouard, 1947
    - Thompson, Kenneth, 1966-1983, undated
    - Tillich, Hannah, 1965-1968, undated
    - Tompkins, Oliver, 1968, 1985-1988
    - Trilling, Lionel and Diana, 1961-1966, undated
    - "T" miscellaneous, 1940-1986, undated
    - Van Dusen, Henry P., 1931-1932, 1962
    - Van Dusen, Hugh and Geraldine, 1968-1987, (2 folders)
    - Vidler, Alexander Roper, 1942-1953, 1968-1985
    - Voss, Carl Hermann, 1973, 1987-1988
    - Watters, Enda, 1973-1974, 1984-1986
    - Welch, Adam C. and Grace M., 1928, 1942, undated
    - Wells, Eddie and Dorothy, 1940-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 53)
    - White, Morton, 1956, 1973, 1986
    - Wilson, Geoffrey and Judy, 1947, 1958-1983, undated
    - Wolf, William J., 1960, 1971, 1980-1986, undated
    - Woodward, E. L. and F. M., 1930-1931, 1943-1971, undated (4 folders, includes typed transcripts) See also Container 56, same heading
    - Wyton, Alec, 1974-1981, 1930-1931, 1943-1971, undated
    - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr., and Gisela, 1956-1976
    - Yale University libraries, New Haven, Conn., 1986
    - Yale University Press, 1983-1987, undated
    - Zeoli, Mari, 1970-1976
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, 1927-1950, 1969-1973, undated
    - Unanswered, 1967-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Unidentified, 1933-1980, undated